borderlands2.com 2013-07-27

# Gearbox Software Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Gearbox® respects the privacy of its online visitors and users of its products. Gearbox recognizes the importance of protecting any information collected from users and has adopted this privacy policy that guides how Gearbox gathers, stores, and uses information from the use of Gearbox products and online sites by users.

This policy is current as of its last revision date. However, please note that this policy may be amended from time to time to reflect changes and additions to the privacy policy. Please check back for the most current version before relying on any of the provisions in this privacy policy.

**Collection and Use of Information**

By using Gearbox's online sites and products, users agree that Gearbox may collect aggregate information, individual information, and personally identifiable information, as defined below. Gearbox may share aggregate information and individual information with other parties. Gearbox shall not share personally identifiable information with other parties, except as described in the policy below.

"Aggregate information" is information that describes the habits, usage patterns, and demographics of users as a group but does not describe or reveal the identity of any particular user.

"Individual information" is information about a user that is presented in a form distinguishable from information relating to other users but not in a form that personally identifies any user or enables the recipient to communicate directly with any user unless agreed to by the user in advance of such communication. This information may be used to improve Gearbox's products and online sites, for internal marketing studies, or simply to collect demographic information about Gearbox's users.

Gearbox may use customer contact information provided by users to send information about Gearbox, including news about product updates, contests, events, and other promotional materials, but only if the users agree to receive such communications. Except in the cases described below, Gearbox will not share personally identifiable information with any third party unless the user agrees to such disclosure in advance. "Personally identifiable information" consists of a user's name, email address, physical address, or other data about the user that enables the recipient to personally identify the user. While Gearbox collects personally identifiable information on a voluntary basis, for certain products and online sites, Gearbox's collection of personally identifiable information may be a requirement for access to the product or site. Personally identifiable information will be processed and stored by Gearbox in databases situated in the United States. Gearbox may allow third parties performing services under contract with Gearbox to access stored information but such access shall only be to the extent necessary to provide those services. In those instances, the third party will be bound by the terms of this privacy policy. In some situations, personally identifiable information you input in connection with this website may be made available to other users of this website. For example, during registration at this website, Gearbox collects a user's email address and nickname, and at the user's option, first and last name. Some of this information may be searchable and available to other users within this website. Gearbox has no obligation to keep the privacy of personally identifiable information that a user makes available to other users via this website or other Gearbox software, such as in multiplayer or other public functions.

Personally identifiable information protected under this privacy policy and collected from users may be done in conjunction with associates under agreement with Gearbox. If an associate of Gearbox is collecting such personally identifiable information within one of our products or online sites, Gearbox will make users aware of this at the time the information is gathered. For example, product registration data for _Borderlands GOTY_ is collected by 2K Games, Inc. If a user does not want to provide this information, the user may choose to opt out of providing this information. Additionally, if providing the information is a requirement of usage, the user may decline to use that particular service or product. When possible, Gearbox will make a reasonable effort to direct users to the privacy policies of these associates. Gearbox's privacy policy does not extend to associates of Gearbox.

Furthermore, external websites and companies with links to and from Gearbox's online sites and products may collect personal information about users. Gearbox's privacy policy does not extend to these external websites and companies. Please refer directly to these companies and websites regarding their privacy policies.

Gearbox may release personally identifiable information to comply with court orders or laws that require us to disclose such information.

**Children Under The Age of 13**

Gearbox will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from any person age 12 and under. Gearbox encourages parents to instruct their children to never give out personal information when online. Parents who are concerned about the transfer of personal information from their children may contact us at privacy@Gearboxsoftware.com to obtain a record of any information held by Gearbox and have it removed at their request.

**Cookies and Other Information on a User's Machine**

Cookies are bits of electronic information that can be transferred to a user's hard drive to customize a person's usage of a product or online site, keep records of a user's access to an online site or product, or store information needed by the user on a regular basis. Use of cookies is typically associated with websites. Gearbox does use cookies on their websites. For example, when you sign into this website, Gearbox stores your user id and a combination of your IP address and time of login as a cookie on your hard drive. This cookie allows you to move from page to page without having to sign in again on each page. Similarly, if you enter information during your session, such as age verification data, this will be stored as a cookie and you will not have to re-enter such information during that session.

Gearbox also stores information on a user's hard drive that is used in conjunction with online play of Gearbox products. This includes a unique authorization key or CD-Key that is either entered by the user or downloaded automatically during product registration. This authorization key is used to identify a user as valid and allow access to Gearbox's products. Information regarding Gearbox billing, your Gearbox account, your Internet connection and the Gearbox software installed on your computer are uploaded to the server in connection with your use of this website and Gearbox software. Gearbox software automatically generates and submits to Gearbox bug reports upon a crash or other fault in the Gearbox software. This automatically generated bug report information may include information about other software or hardware on a user's system. Gearbox does not associate and store the automatically generated bug report information with personally identifiable information. Any bug reporting information manually submitted by users (e.g. through Gearbox's Bug Reporter form) is associated and stored with personally identifiable information. Users should also be aware that game play information disclosed during multiplayer game play (e.g. player name and current player statistics) is public information and may be displayed to other users.

**Chat Forums, Etc.**

From time to time, Gearbox's online products may provide chat forums, bulletin boards, or instant messaging tools to users. Any information that is disclosed in chat forums or bulletin boards is public information, and users who message one another may not know each other personally. Users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in such chat forums.

**Choice/Opt-out**

Gearbox gives users the option of discontinuing receipt of promotional email communications from Gearbox. Instructions for discontinuing receipt of promotional email communications from Gearbox will be provided in such subsequent email communications to users.

**Storage and Security of Information**

Personally identifiable information will be processed and stored by Gearbox in databases hosted in the United States. Gearbox has taken reasonable steps to protect the information users share with us, including, but not limited to, setup of processes, equipment and software to avoid unauthorized access or disclosure of this information. 

**Corrections, Updates and Removal of Information**

If you are concerned about the accuracy of personal information maintained by Gearbox or would like your personal information removed from Gearbox's records, please contact us by emailing privacy@Gearboxsoftware.com for review, update, or removal of personal information.

**Contacting Gearbox**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, or the privacy practices of Gearbox, please contact us by emailing [**privacy@Gearboxsoftware.com**](mailto:privacy@valvesoftware.com).

_Revision Date: September 7, 2010_
